Student Demonstrations Files, ca. 1933-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Student Demonstrations Files
ca. 1933-[ongoing]
Smith College.
RG 80 UUID:6d7bc4f3-8d0b-4491-aaaf-36f921964459
2 boxes (.8 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The Student Demonstrations files contain a wide range of information about the history of political demonstrations at Smith College.
The Student Demonstrations files document how Smith College students have expressed their opposition to national and local issues through rallies and protests since 1933. Major events such as the United States' involvement in World War II, presidential elections, and segregation prompted the majority of student demonstrations from the 1930s to 1960s. Issues of the 1980s and 1990s include opposition to the Persian Gulf War, support for Ada Comstock Scholars, as well as rallies to help improve women's safety on college campuses.
The 1986 occupation of College Hall makes up the largest portion of the Student Demonstration files. These folders contain both primary and secondary sources, documenting Smith students' opposition to the Board of Trustees' investment in South African companies that contributed to apartheid.
The Student Demonstrations files include documents that relate to demonstrations and protests conducted by Smith College students from 1933 to present. These activities include rallies and campaigns regarding national and local issues, ranging from opposition to U.S. wars abroad to conflicts of racism on the Smith campus. Types of materials include academic papers, news clippings, newsletters, photographs, protest signs, and student diaries.
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
The Student Demonstrations files were donated to the Smith College Archives over a period of time from a variety of sources.
Researchers should also view:
- 80. College Hall Occupation Oral History Project
- 80. Student Strike 1970
- Demonstrations 1933-35 (Box 3023, Folder 1)
- Demonstrations - Riots 1936-37 (Box 3023, Folder 2)
- Demonstrations 1940-49 (Box 3023, Folder 3)
- Demonstrations - Photos 1950-59 (Box 3023, Folder 4)
- Demonstrations 1960-65 (Box 3023, Folder 5)
- Demonstrations 1965-66 (Box 3023, Folder 6)
- Demonstrations 1966-67 (Box 3023, Folder 7)
- Demonstrations 1967-68 (Box 3023, Folder 8)
- Demonstrations - News clippings, local March 1967 (Box 3023, Folder 9)
- Demonstrations - News clippings, local 1967 (Box 3023, Folder 10)
- Demonstrations - Fast For Peace 1968 (Box 3023, Folder 11)
- Demonstrations - News clippings, local 1968 (Box 3023, Folder 12)
- Demonstrations 1968-69 (Box 3023, Folder 13)
- Demonstrations - News clippings, local 1968-69 (Box 3023, Folder 14)
- Demonstrations - Photographs October 1969 (Box 3023, Folder 15)
- Demonstrations - Day of Dialogue 1969 (Box 3023, Folder 16)
- Demonstrations - Work for Peace October 1969 (Box 3023, Folder 17)
- Demonstrations - National Student Strike 1969-70 (Box 3023, Folder 18)
- Demonstrations 1970-72 (Box 3023, Folder 19)
- Demonstrations - News clippings 1971-72 (Box 3023, Folder 20)
- Demonstrations 1973-74 (Box 3023, Folder 21)
- Demonstrations - South Africa 1975-80 (Box 3023, Folder 22)
- Demonstrations 1981 (Box 3023, Folder 23)
- Demonstrations 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 24)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - "Why Smith, Why Now?" - Donna Kenny 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 25)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - "It Happened at Smith" - Maureen Dooley Lawrence 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 26)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - Diaries 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 27)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - Notes by Rebecca Loveland, Class of 1988 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 28)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - Signs 1986 (Box 3023, Folder 29)
- Demonstrations - Statements of Support - 2 Notes from Mary Maples Dunn 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 1)
- Demonstrations - Student Proposal for Settlement 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 2)
- Demonstrations - Lists of People at Sit-in & Supporters 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 3)
- Demonstrations - Trustee Investment Policy Statements 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 4)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - Press Coverage and Public Relations 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 5)
- Demonstrations - College Hall Occupation - Community Policy Committee Report October 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 6)
- Demonstrations - Women's March for Life - Washington, D.C. 1986 (Box 3023.1, Folder 7)
- Demonstrations - C.I.A. Recruiting 1987 (Box 3023.1, Folder 8)
- Demonstrations - Space for Multicultural Organizations 1990 (Box 3023.1, Folder 9)
- Demonstrations - Persian Gulf War 1991 (Box 3023.1, Folder 10)
- Demonstrations - United Student Employee Delegation (USED) 1991 (Box 3023.1, Folder 11)
- Demonstrations - Rodney King Verdict 1992 (Box 3023.1, Folder 12)
- Demonstrations - Rally for Ada's 1994 (Box 3023.1, Folder 13)
- Demonstrations - Chain for Change 1996 (Box 3023.1, Folder 14)
- Demonstrations 1997-98 (Box 3023.1, Folder 15)
- Demonstrations 1999 (Box 3023.1, Folder 16)
- Demonstrations - Blackface Incident - Posters, etc. 2007 (Box 3023.1, Folder 17)